# Kavish Hukmani

(650) 683-5325 ♦ kshukmani@ucdavis.edu ♦ San Francisco, CA

linkedin.com/in/kavish-hukmani ◆ github.com/DoubleGremlin181 ◆ kavishhukmani.me

#### **PROFILE**

Master of Science in Business Analytics candidate at UC Davis with a strong background in Computer Engineering and a hands-on approach to problem solving.

Specialties: Machine Learning, Data Analytics, Statistical Exploration, Optimization, Big Data, Computer Vision

Programming Languages: Python, SQL dialects (MySQL, BigQuery, MS SQL), R, Java

Technologies: Linux, Tableau, Gurobi, AWS, GCP, Advanced Excel, Git

Certifications: AWS Academy Cloud Foundations, UCSD Big Data Specialization, DeepLearning.AI Deep Learning

Specialization

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of California, Davis

San Francisco, CA

Master of Science, Business Analytics

Expected Jun. 2021

Highlighted Coursework: Machine Learning, Advanced Statistics, Big Data Analytics, Cloud Computing

## **Manipal Institute of Technology**

Manipal, India

Bachelor of Technology, Major in Computer and Communication Engineering, Minor in Big Data

Aug. 2020

Highlighted Coursework: Data Mining and Predictive Analysis, Computer Vision, Pattern Recognition

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Student Practicum: Angel Flight West**

San Francisco, CA

**Graduate Student Data Analyst** 

Oct. 2021 - Jun. 2022

As a part of the MSBA practicum, worked with Angel Flight West, a non-profit organization that provides free non-emergency medical flights to patients in need.

- Saved over 500 flights a year from being canceled last minute by improving the accuracy of the flight cancellation risk assessment models using Azure ML.
- Used Google Analytics to analyze user drop-off in the new patient intake forms and conducted A/B tests to increase form completions.
- Performed ETL jobs on 5 years of flight data for ad-hoc analysis with SQL and Python.

#### Impact Analytics

Bengaluru, India

**Data Scientist** 

Aug. 2020 - Jun. 2021

**Data Science Intern** 

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

Worked in the AI/Optimization team at Impact Analytics, a fast-growing startup providing SaaS solutions to retailers in the fashion and CPG markets.

- Enabled Tommy Hilfiger, Puma, and Calvin Klein to optimize their promotions and inventory allocation by building Linear Programming models in Gurobi. Received a Spot Award for improvements in runtime.
- Trained a mobile vision CNN to identify image quality issues such as blur, tilt, and irrelevance.
- Maintained several critical APIs and servers used by client facing software.
- Helped develop a coupon book creator for a Fortune 500 warehouse club chain.

### **PROJECTS**

**Solving Twisty Puzzles using Reinforcement Learning**: Published a paper and accompanying open-source library Contributor to **D2ACQ**: An open-source online video game audio quiz

DotA 2 Icon GAN: Trained a GAN to generate new character skill icons for the video game DotA 2

### **ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS**

Awards: MSBA Fellowship at UC Davis, Spot Award at Impact Analytics

Leadership: Core Committee Member and Head of Outstation Management for multiple college festivals.